<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>the education system of german</title>
    <description>What is the definition of education? Let's first know the  meaning of education and make changes.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 16:38:46 +0900</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 16:38:46 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>what is meaning a school in Korea (or your country) in your life experience? and do you think Korean student missing important things?</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-meaning-a-school-in-korea-or-your-country-in-your-life-experience-and-do-you-think-korea-student-missing-important-things&quot;&gt;what is meaning a school in Korea (or your country) in your life experience? and do you think Korea student missing important things?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;learn-new-things-from-education-live-together-need-no-more-competition&quot;&gt;learn new things from education, live together. need no more competition.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1590069479230-b0e5b713db88?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=800&amp;amp;q=60&quot; alt=&quot;german&quot; title=&quot;german.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about education and what you have experience in your life. do you think school is important for children? if your answer is yes, let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;back to write. to be honest, my opinion is education is important. some students learn new knowledge form education, some students learn a new skill to live world. and students learn to live together in the future at the school, without racism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to me, school meaning is camp to live together with another person. to me, school meaning is to learn how can make relationships with another person. But I think almost Korea student learn competition at school first. and then they learn a lot of subject for the test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was growing up in Korea until now. of course, I was thinking about what I learned at school past, until after Australia working holiday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found this reason. I learned the only subject for the College Scholastic Ability Test (CSAT) without discussion. there is no discussion, there is no critical education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember my high school life. studied hard no reason. even class friends studied the same as me. I thought this is terrible for the future, and I thought about my life. “why I study hard every day?” “do I have to stay at school morning- night?”I couldn’t learn how can I found an answer about some question by 19 years my self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s my personal life experience, but it’s my one of opinions this is a problem of Korea education system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Korea education is the education of competition. we need to realise this is one of the biggest problems for future generations as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s  Korea school building.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/proxy/eFhU_bFdPTba29xjVXyJKK-xFypIRHc7muvZvy5-tDc6R_17TD52cX2RGZwAu-HjlTcF9TbfeGWTbbQwSxiSoz2ojqzTzXc_esklnwuxwTcX8vqkfXg&quot; alt=&quot;Korea&quot; title=&quot;Korea.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;and you can see how they study hard all day.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.hanyang.ac.kr/documents/20182/ad37ad51-0906-4511-a3af-12973a59f68c&quot; alt=&quot;Korea&quot; title=&quot;Korea.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They are reading a lot of book for the College Scholastic Ability Test.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cms.qz.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/south-korea-studying.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1600&amp;amp;h=900&amp;amp;crop=1&quot; alt=&quot;Korea&quot; title=&quot;Korea.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I heard about Finland, german, or another country education system.&lt;/strong&gt;
some countries student studies only less 6 class a day. and german student study without a test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I started to research the England education system for figures out what is the biggest difference. England education system is different compare Korea education system.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UK offers specialized training based on student abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, according to the majors the student wants to study, the required subjects are selectively selected to study and the grades of the subjects studied when going to college are reflected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From childhood, students in England experience essay-oriented problems to improve their comprehension, thinking, and logic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All tests in the UK, for example, GCSE, A-Level, Foundation, are all questions (subjective)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advanced sports such as rugby, fencing, cricket, horseback riding, rowing, ballet, and essential subjects such as musical instrument lessons, arts, and plays are enjoyed on-campus as performances and related training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you look at English students, you will be required to learn 10 subjects from elementary school (private school only), including English, mathematics, science, geography, history, sociology, politics, art, computers, and design technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason for studying these subjects is because they learn about the related fields of each major and the causality of how it is applied and reflected in reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;British schools are largely divided into short breaks of about a week in the semester (Summer Break) from mid-June to the beginning of the new school year from the beginning of the new school year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are about one week in mid-February, three weeks in early April (Easter), one week in late May, seven to eight weeks in summer vacation, and one week in mid-October or late.&lt;a href=&quot;https://post.naver.com/viewer/postView.nhn?volumeNo=16316616&amp;amp;memberNo=36835023&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, during this period, the school mainly conducts research or project tasks, and conducts consistent education so that students can study for themselves, reach conclusions through data research and research, and improve problem solving skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through a special curriculum, students can find ways to study difficult subjects themselves. Making it easy to get to the subject is a characteristic of British education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if you need more information about this, check here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://post.naver.com/viewer/postView.nhn?volumeNo=16316616&amp;amp;memberNo=36835023&quot;&gt;blog about England education&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s think about next question.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-you-think-korea-student-missing-important-things&quot;&gt;do you think Korea student missing important things?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My opinion is Korea student is can’t learn to find a way to answer study, use research at school if the Korea education system is never changing to a better solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;recently, the situation is changing now. but it is not enough for a change better way of future generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for example England case and Korea case, From the difference between the curriculum and the class you can found this fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s see Korea case first.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basic academic knowledge and importance of compulsory subjects continue to be emphasized from elementary to law school.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6tw2Srx8F3g&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/75FxLKg1sXM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subjects of special importance are subjects other than Korean, English, Mathematics, and Science, and focus on education in one direction.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continually learning English and second foreign languages.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in the case of the second foreign language, it is for college entrance exams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Korea students a study only grammar a lot, and they are remembering hard English word for college entrance exams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8Dgww5kXCdI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yRyssWqeg2Y&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;**Teacher’s moving class. (except for certain subjects, students do not move) **&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already graduated from high school  in 2007. but I remember I was moving to the classroom to classroom for only Japanese class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extensive curriculum irrelevant to college and future hopes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;but England case is different.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The content of the lessons varies significantly depending on the learning method of the lower and upper grades.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teaching students to be interested and have fun in some of the less’academic’ areas, such as mental health, hobbies and skills.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DD9LK3vNWiU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fDW50ZJLDuo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/U2uqoPMeDKg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7Xd6NjlCMH4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aims to cultivate language proficiency so that students can learn and practice step by step, systematically from low grade.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Students move from classroom to classroom-more specialized and systematic lessons, taking responsibility for class preparation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3-4 specialized subject learning related to majors and professions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the education system is totally different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so we need an education revolution, no more don’t need to change a little part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we need no more competition, no more Education that hurts self-esteem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this slogan is important for future generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“school is a place to learn to live together basically”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 12:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//german-6/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//german-6/</guid>
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>Revolution</category>
        
        <category>system</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        
        <category>krfuture</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>정책 변화 과정 중에 발견된 문제와 해결방안. Willy Brandt의 교육정책</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;willy-brandt의-교육정책&quot;&gt;Willy Brandt의 교육정책&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;독일의-개선방안--교육-변화-역사&quot;&gt;독일의 개선방안 &amp;amp; 교육 변화 역사&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;독일을 보면 위치가 유럽에 있는 것을 볼 수 있다. 그러면 나라의 역사도 변화가 많았다는 것을 예상할 수 있고, 교육의 역사도 있을 것으로 예상된다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;유럽은 수 많은 변화가 있었고 특히 19세기에 현대 기술과 산업화로 인해서 새로운 학교 교육 시스템이 필요했다. 물론 독일도 유럽의 국가로 변화가 있었다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1579626747178-6b17360cbf44?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=800&amp;amp;q=60&quot; alt=&quot;german&quot; title=&quot;german.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;현재의 독일 교육 시스템 이해를 위한 역사를 보면&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;먼저 19세기 유럽은 초등학교와 라틴어 또는 문법, 학교, 중등학교, 대학교를 포함한 오래된 학교들과 함께, 새로운 기술, 상업적 시대를 반영한 정확한 과학과 현대 언어를 강조하는 소위 현대적인 학교들이 개발되었다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;직업학교도 많이 생겼고, 학교 시스템에 대해서 국가의 영향력이 강해졌다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;독일은 프러시아 국가의 등장과 함께 국가가 교육에 개입하기 시작했다.&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prussian_education_system&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Education_in_Germany&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1717년 프레데릭 윌리엄 1세는 모든 아이들에게 가능하다면 학교에 다니라고 명령했고 1736년에 특정 지방에 학교를 설립하라는 칙령에 의해서 1763년 프레데릭 2세가 의무 학교 출석의 원칙을 주장하는 근거가 되었다. 그러나 삶에 필요한 지식과 분야가 없는 교육과정 이었다. 홈볼트의 중등교육 정책으로 1810년에 교사를 양성하기 위한 국가고시와 자격증 시험이 도입되었다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;교사로서 자격이 없는 신학생들이 학교에서 가르칠 수 있도록 허용했던 당시의 관행을 없애고 교직 현장을 프로이센의 교육진보 최전선으로 만들고자 했다. 이 때 아비투르가 부할한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;그 후에, 1815년에 주 정부가 모든 독일의 중학교에 교육을 위한 기준을 만들 수 있었고 (독일은 교육정책이 주 정부마다 다르다) 시간이 지나면서 점차 현재의 교육 과정 기초가 만들어졌다. 프러시아의 중등학교 공식분류는 이렇다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) &lt;strong&gt;the Classical nine-year &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/topic/Gymnasium-German-school&quot;&gt;Gymnasium&lt;/a&gt;, with a curriculum that included Latin, Greek, and a modern language.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9 년 라틴어과정, 그리스어 및 현대 언어를 포함한 커리큘럼&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(2) &lt;strong&gt;the semi-Classical nine-year Realgymnasium, with a more modern curriculum that included, in addition to Latin and modern languages, the natural sciences and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/science/mathematics&quot;&gt;mathematics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;라틴어, 현대언어, 수학과정을 포함한 커리큘럼&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(3) &lt;strong&gt;the modern six-year Realschule or nine-year Oberrealschule, with a curriculum of sciences and mathematics.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;과학과  수학과정을 포함한 현대 교과과정. (Realschule 6년 or Oberrealschule 9년)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;이 세가지의  체계적인 교육 커리큘럼이 나왔다. 이 당시에 나온 교육 과정이 독일을 산업 국가로 만드는 원동력이 되었다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;여학교도 있었으나20세기 까지 모든 사람이 만족하는 교육 정책은 나오지 못 했다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;그러다가 19세기에 고등 교육에 대한 논의가 이루어 졌고 또 다른 변화가 이루어졌다.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/topic/education/Social-reconstructionist-education#ref47653&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;그러면 이제 좀 더 깊이 알아보자&lt;/strong&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;독일 교육의 역사를 보면 비극적인 교육이 이루어진 기록이 있다. 또한 그 교육의 결과는 600만명 유대인이 학살 당하고 전쟁이라는 모습이었다. 우리는, 전 세계 사람들은 아직도 기억하고 있다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;처음에 1871년에  독일제국이 만들어 지고 나서는 여성을 위한 최초의 중등학교를 국가가 공식으로 인정했다. 1894년과 1908년에는 여성을 위한 학교가 더 확장되었다.6세부터 16세 까지 이 학교에서 여성들이 공부했고  Lyzeum으로 불렸다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;이 당시에 과학과 수학과정을 포함한 현대 교과과정이 있는 Oberrealschule는 &lt;strong&gt;2 가지 코스&lt;/strong&gt;로 나눴다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1)  &lt;strong&gt;2년과정인 *Frauenschule&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2)  &lt;strong&gt;예비 초등학교 교사를 위한 4 년 과정으로 공부하는 Lehrerinnenseminar&lt;/strong&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;또한 직업교육을 위한 중등학교가 더 설립되었다. 이 학교는 시간제 교육을 통한 견습훈련이  주 목적이었다. 그후 1919년에 바이마르 공화국이 나오면서 이제는 무료로 보편적 4 년 초등학교인Grundschule을 대부분의 학생들이 다닐 수 있게 되었다. 학교에서 학생들은 또 다른 4 년 과정을 계속 공부할 수 도 있었다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;교육을 위해서 비용을 지불 할 수 있었던 사람들은 Mittelschule로 가서 1 년 또는 2 년 더 도전적인 커리큘럼을 제공받으면서 공부했다. 4 학년 이후 엄격한 입학 시험을 통과하면 학생들은 4 가지 중등 학교 중 한 학교로 입학 할 수 있었다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;이제 다음 교육과정에서 앞에서 말한 파쇼 교육이 나온다. 나치독일시대에 히틀러라는 사람이 독일 국가의 리더가 되면서 독일 사회는 점차 전체주의로 변했고 교육도 전체주의를 따라가는 교육이 되었다. 1933년부터 독일 문화는 대우 되어야 한다는 전제로 나치 신앙을 교과과정에 포함시켰다. 생물학이 “인종 과학”으로 변했고 대부분의 교육과정은 변하지 않았다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;하지만 인종차멸적인 교육이 이루어졌고 독일인이 가장 위대하다는 교육을 받은 1930년, 1940년 당시의 독일인 군인에 의해서 600만명의 유태인이 가스로, 인권은 존중받지 못한 상태로 학살당했다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;빌리 브란트 (Willy Brandt)는 잘못된 교육의 결과를 보고 다시는 똑같은 비극이 이루어 지지 않기를 바랬고 2차 세계대전 전쟁 패전 후 독일을 선거를 통해서 이끄는 총리로 정권교체를 이루어냈다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;빌리 브란트의 민주주의는 독일의 교육에도 똑같이 적용되었고 반 권위주의 교육, 비판교육, 저항권 교육등 저항교육이 독일에 정착이 되었다. 또한 이 당시에 국가의 대부분 시설이 파괴된 상태애서도 대학등록금을 대학생이 내지 않고 공부 할 수 있게 “바푀크” 라는 제도를 도입했다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;파쇼교육과는 다른 새로운 독일교육이 시작되는 순간이라고 나는 생각한다. 심지어 대학의 운영권중 3분에 1은 학생에게 권한을 주는 정책도 시행되었고 교수, 학생, 강사, 총장선출의 권한을 학생이 가질 수 있게 했다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;그 당시 독일 정부는 비판교육으로 나치의 영향을 없애고자 했으며 주 정부의 교육개혁 자율성을 유지되었다. 이 당시 독일의 교육정책을 보면 한 마디로 모험이다. 국가 재건과 함께 교육도 다시 재건한 것이다. 물론 이때 민주주의도 교육 속에 자연스럽게 스며들었다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;교육정책에서 의무교육은 유지되었다.  6세에서 18세 까지는 의무교육이고 학생들은 초등학교에서 ( &lt;em&gt;Grundschule&lt;/em&gt; ) 한 명의 교사와 같이 (한국과는 다른 시스템) 4년을 공부하고 다른 중등학교 커리큘럼에 따라서  한 학교에서6년을 공부하거나, 아니면 2년을 공부한다&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;자세히 보면 초등학교 졸업 후에 진로탐색 기간이 있다. 이 기간에도 비판, 반 권위주의, 저항권 교육의 영향을 학생들이 받을 것으로 예상한다.  중요한 것은 다양한 경로로 학생들이 자신이 누군지 알고 배움의 기회를 계속 가질 수 있다. 대학교를 가서 더 공부할 지, 아니면 직업교육을 받고 사회생활을 할 지 선택을 할 수 있다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“바푀크” 정책으로 인한 영향으로 중등교육 학비도 거의 없다고 한다. 한국처럼 대부분 대학교를 가는 한가지 방향만 있는 것이 아닌 것을 알 수 있다. 대학 학비도 국가에서 지원해주면서 목표를 가지고 학생이 부담없이 미래를 준비 할 수 있는 기회를 가진다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;물론 단점도 있다고 현지인들은 말한다. 하지만 학교에서 배우는 것을 그대로 받아들이는 것이 아닌 비판적으로 보면서 학교에서 정치교육과 생태교육, 성교육 등을 통해서 성장한다면, 민주주의를 작게 배울 수 있는 환경이라면 “독일학생들은 적어도 생각하는 훈련은 자연스럽게 하지 않을까?!“ 라고 나는 생각한다. 게다가 조상들의 잘못을 그대로 배우고 과거의 잘못을 다시는 하지 않아야 한다고 삶에서 느끼는 학생들로 자연스럽게 변한다고 생각되기도 한다.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 20:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//german-5/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//german-5/</guid>
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>Revolution</category>
        
        <category>system</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        
        <category>krfuture</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>독일생활을 오래 한 김누리 교수님의 의견</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;독일생활을-오래-한-김누리-교수님의-의견&quot;&gt;독일생활을 오래 한 김누리 교수님의 의견&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;교수님은 독일의 교육은 Educate = 교육하다 라는 의미를 잘 살린 예시라고 본다. E =밖으로 duce + ate = 이끌다가 합쳐져서 각 사람의 가능성을 알고 이끌어 내야 한다는 것이 교수님이 주장하는 교육의 진정한 의미이다. 한 단어로 말하자면 통찰력을 키워주는 교육 이자 “비판 교육” “ 아우슈비츠 교육” 이라고 할 수 있다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘&lt;u&gt;**아우슈비츠 교육 = 비판교육**&lt;/u&gt;’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;각 학생의 다른 가능성을 살려주고 꺼내 주어야 하는 교사가 독일도 학교마다 필요하다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;초등학교 교사를 위해서는 최소 6년의 준비기간 / 중 고등학교 교사는 8년 ~ 10년의 준비기간이 필요하다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;대학에서 먼저 교직과목을 4년동안 공부 후에 1차 국가고시 시험과정을 거쳐간다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2차 국가고시는2~3년의 수습 교사 생활 후에 볼 수 있다. 여기서 중 고등학교 교사는  추가로 논문을 작성해야 한다. 이 논문은 대부분 박사논문이다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;결국 독일 교육은 교사의 능력을 우선으로 철저하게 준비하게 하는 과정을 거쳐서 학생을 진정으로 사람답게 만드는 교육이라고 생각이 들 수 밖에 없다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;한 가지 예시로 초등학교(Primary Education) 교육에서는 한 명의 교사가 처음 만난 학생을 4년동안 같이 한다. 즉 학생의 가능성을 제대로 알고 강한 자아로 키울 수 있는 환경 안에서 학생들은 선생님하고 좋은 관계를 가지면서 자라날 수 있다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;나는 이러한 방식은 택한 독일 교육이 지금의 학생부터 부모세대까지 시민의식이 성장하게 한 원동력이라고 본다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;과거에 히틀러에 의한 파쇼교육이 이루어 졌던 역사가 있다. 파쇼교육은 불평등과 인종주의제국주의를 신념으로 여기는 파시스트들의 교육원리이다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;이 교육의 결과 독일은 유태인을 학살하고,  2차 세계대전을 시작한 국가가 되었고 전쟁 후 패전한 국가가 되었다. 모든 것이 파괴되었고 재건해야만 했던 아픈 역사를 독일인들은 아직도 기억하고 있다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;독일의 대부분 집 앞에 있는 걸림돌(stolperstein)인 슈톨퍼슈타인이 독일인이 과거를 기억하는 하나의 예시이다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/04/ScreenShotgr1.png&quot; alt=&quot;germany's education system&quot; title=&quot;germany's education system.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-독일인이 느끼는 마음속의 걸림돌&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/04/ScreenShotgr2.png&quot; alt=&quot;germany's education system&quot; title=&quot;germany's education system.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;교수님이 말하는 독일 교육 4가지 방식을 정리하면&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;인간이 가진 고유한 능력을 끌어내기&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;강한 자아를 가진 학생으로 키우는 것.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;타인과 같이 살아가는 방법을 알게하기.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;행복의 감수성을 높여주기&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;이렇게 정리할 수 있다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;심지어 독일의 학교에는 행복이라는 과목까지 있을 정도로 다른 나라와는 다르다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;시험은 한국같이 객관식 시험이 없다고 교수님은 말하고 있다. 시험 보는 날자는 비밀이며 학교에서 학생들간의 경쟁은 없다고 한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;그리고 김누리 교수님은 한국 교육에는 없는 3 가지가 독일 교육에는 있다고 한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;성교육 – 독일만의 남다른 성교육으로 실용적으로 재미있게 성교육을 학생들을 대상으로 한다. 성적 자기 결정권을 존중하게 하는 것이 독일의 성교육의 목표이다. 책임감과 생명윤리를 학생들이 스스로 알 수 있게 한다. 성에 대한 올바른 판단을 바탕으로 윤리적 판단을 금지한다.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;예시로 학생들은 선생님한테 섹스나 자위등 궁금한 것을 자유롭게 질문을 한다.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://m.cpbc.co.kr/CMS/newspaper/2018/01/rc/710078_1.1_titleImage_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sex education in german&quot; title=&quot;sex education in german.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://m.cpbc.co.kr/paper/view.php?cid=710078&amp;amp;path=201801&quot;&gt;독일 성교육관련 link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;정치교육 – 학생들이 스스로  누가 선동가인지 판단 가능하게 하고 효과적으로 시위하는 방법을 배운다. 그리고 학생들이 토론 후 시위구호나 저항을 할 수 있는 생각을 할 수 있게 정치교육을 한다. 더 나아가서 타인과의 관계를 어떻게 해야하는지 자연스럽게 배운다.  10대들의 의견이 정치에 그대로 반영되는 곳이 지금의 독일이다. 또한 이것이 진정한 정치교육이다.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img1.daumcdn.net/thumb/R1280x0/?scode=mtistory2&amp;amp;fname=https%3A%2F%2Fk.kakaocdn.net%2Fdn%2FmnEPW%2FbtqCvyGGaqc%2FVXIBbkWpWVmaEKsLLIwKk1%2Fimg.png&quot; alt=&quot;politiccal education in german&quot; title=&quot;politiccal education in german.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img1.daumcdn.net/thumb/R1280x0/?scode=mtistory2&amp;amp;fname=https%3A%2F%2Fk.kakaocdn.net%2Fdn%2FmitzA%2FbtqCwW1x1VI%2FJqTjFwshcKQwazukmwn1tK%2Fimg.png&quot; alt=&quot;politiccal education in german&quot; title=&quot;politiccal education in german.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img1.daumcdn.net/thumb/R1280x0/?scode=mtistory2&amp;amp;fname=https%3A%2F%2Fk.kakaocdn.net%2Fdn%2FbiZBx3%2FbtqCzBWrHgM%2FTsMtvdjN0cB8HjwBinlVhk%2Fimg.png&quot; alt=&quot;politiccal education in german&quot; title=&quot;politiccal education in german.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img1.daumcdn.net/thumb/R1280x0/?scode=mtistory2&amp;amp;fname=https%3A%2F%2Fk.kakaocdn.net%2Fdn%2FzDaxi%2FbtqCvyT8VCY%2Fe0SPa0lHZCNkBAEdczeyOK%2Fimg.png&quot; alt=&quot;politiccal education in german&quot; title=&quot;politiccal education in german.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;생태교육 – 환경을 의해서 불편함을 참는 독일인을 보면 생태교육의 중요성을 알 수 있다. 독일의 학생들은 소비를 하면서 스스로 환경오염을 한다는 사실을 느끼고 삶에서 소비를 줄인다고 한다. 자연과의 관계를 돌아보는 교육이 독일의 생태교육이다. 한가지 예시로 독일에는 플록샴 (Flugscham)이라고 부르는 운동이 있다. 비행기를 타지 말고 다니자는 운동이다. 온실가스의 주범을 스스로 타지 않고자 자발적으로 독일 시민들이 결정한 것이다.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img1.daumcdn.net/thumb/R1280x0/?scode=mtistory2&amp;amp;fname=https%3A%2F%2Fk.kakaocdn.net%2Fdn%2FbT5Gcn%2FbtqCrPW1NJZ%2FKRA4omH655yeGMQVcDgSGk%2Fimg.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ecological education in german&quot; title=&quot;Ecological education in german.&quot; style=&quot;zoom:80%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img1.daumcdn.net/thumb/R1280x0/?scode=mtistory2&amp;amp;fname=https%3A%2F%2Fk.kakaocdn.net%2Fdn%2FsnO05%2FbtqCsH5okOQ%2F0720ZacBmTuOPiMIAhiv6K%2Fimg.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ecological education in german&quot; title=&quot;Ecological education in german.&quot; style=&quot;zoom:80%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img1.daumcdn.net/thumb/R1280x0/?scode=mtistory2&amp;amp;fname=https%3A%2F%2Fk.kakaocdn.net%2Fdn%2FdgDx5q%2FbtqCxQtgPak%2FKiowyVdzSL9iHoWaJHfir0%2Fimg.png&quot; alt=&quot;politiccal education in german&quot; title=&quot;Ecological education in german.&quot; style=&quot;zoom:80%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;서독의 총리인 빌리 브란트는 독일을 교육사회로 만들고자 했고 그의 계획을 실제로 이루어 졌다. “교육에 차별이 있어서는 안된다”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;빌리 브란트는 바퓌크라는 제도는 만들어서 교육은 생활비를 지원 받으면서 공부하게 하고 나증에 갚아 나가에 함으로서 교육사회가 사회개혁으로 이루어진 독일을 지금 우리는 보고있다&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img1.daumcdn.net/thumb/R1280x0/?scode=mtistory2&amp;amp;fname=https%3A%2F%2Fk.kakaocdn.net%2Fdn%2Ft8cnj%2FbtqCsHEpRbR%2FpR9h36tdfBOHjdIci3PIbK%2Fimg.png&quot; alt=&quot;politiccal education in german&quot; title=&quot;Ecological education in german.&quot; style=&quot;zoom:80%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img1.daumcdn.net/thumb/R1280x0/?scode=mtistory2&amp;amp;fname=https%3A%2F%2Fk.kakaocdn.net%2Fdn%2Fdf7jLF%2FbtqCuZYLWDz%2F26KwhRyWKt0ixqdsqIAZ5K%2Fimg.png&quot; alt=&quot;politiccal education in german&quot; title=&quot;politiccal education in german.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img1.daumcdn.net/thumb/R1280x0/?scode=mtistory2&amp;amp;fname=https%3A%2F%2Fk.kakaocdn.net%2Fdn%2FSZxJY%2FbtqCwX7gorC%2FBvkD3uv3AAko0oUUDHKSQ0%2Fimg.png&quot; alt=&quot;politiccal education in german&quot; title=&quot;politiccal education in german.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img1.daumcdn.net/thumb/R1280x0/?scode=mtistory2&amp;amp;fname=https%3A%2F%2Fk.kakaocdn.net%2Fdn%2FboqkZU%2FbtqCyndjSGu%2F3cg3xtxoBG74dHG48oBMYK%2Fimg.png&quot; alt=&quot;politiccal education in german&quot; title=&quot;politiccal education in german.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img1.daumcdn.net/thumb/R1280x0/?scode=mtistory2&amp;amp;fname=https%3A%2F%2Fk.kakaocdn.net%2Fdn%2Fcf5Cpp%2FbtqCuYZRsxj%2F9r8bqzlwnraiV3HTMLHJg0%2Fimg.png&quot; alt=&quot;politiccal education in german&quot; title=&quot;politiccal education in german.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;그러면 현재 한국교육은 어떤지 알아보자.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;김누리 교수님은 한국 교육은 사람을 기르는 교육은 한 적인 없다고 주장한다. 한국교육의 목표는 민주시민을 기르는 교육이었으나 현실은 자본이 점령한 교육, 반(反)교육이라고 한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;외세 지배 30년에 의한 일본을 위한 교육 / 독재 정권 40년에 의한 반공 전사. 산업 역군의 위한 교육 / 민주정부 30년 동안은 인적자원을 위한 교육 이었다고 한다. 100년 한국 교육은  참혹했다고 한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;학생들 스스로 자존감이 낮아지게 하는 교육이 현재의 한국 교육이라는 것이다. 외우는 것은 강점이나 그 지식을 활용 하는 방법은 배우지 못한다. 나도 이 의견에 동의한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;초등학교, 중학교, 고등학교 생활을 12 년 동안 하면서 연대와 공감, 같이 살아가는 방법을 배우는 것이 아닌 경쟁 속에서 입시제도에서 비정상적으로 탄생한 수능이라는 시험을 거쳐서 병들고 상처받은 상태로 대학교를 간다. 대학교에서도 사회적으로 연대를 하는 것이 아닌 또 다른 경쟁을 한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;공교육의 현장인 학교에서 배우지 못한 진정한 교육의 의미를 대학교에는 배우지 못하는 것이 현실이다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;위에서 말 했듯이Educate 단어는 교육하다라는 의미이다. 그러면 E =밖으로 duce + ate = 이끌다가 합쳐져서 각 사람의 가능성을 알고 이끌어 내야 한다는 것이 교수님이 주장하는 교육의 진정한 의미이다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;프랑스 사람 베라르디는 한국교육을 이렇게 비판했으며 나는 정확하게 봤다고 생각한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/04/ScreenShotgr3.png&quot; alt=&quot;germany's education system&quot; title=&quot;germany's education system.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;그러면 한국 교육은 어떻게 변해야 할까? 교수님은 현재의 입시제도를 폐지하고 완전히 다른 방향으로 가야 한다고 한다. 근본적인 교육목표를 바꿔야 한다고 한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;성숙한 인간이자 민주주의자를 기르는 교육&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;연대, 공감교육으로 변화되는 교육&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;모든 학생들이 평등하게 기회가 주어지는 교육&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;그러면서 현재 점진적으로 할 수 있는 대안을 강연에서 소개한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;국립대학을 네트워크와 하고 서열구조가 없어져야 한다고 한다. 또한 대학 등록금을 폐지하고 국가에서 공부를 할 수 있게 지원해야 한다고 한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;그러면 이제는 대학가는 것이 말 그대로 또 다른 기회가 될 것이라고 교수님은 말한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;교수님의 교육혁명과정을 보면 변화의 과정에서 기득권의 거대한 저항이 있을 것이라고 예상하면서 사교육 시장도 저항이 있을 것이 분명하다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;그러나 이제는 “교육 혁명” 이 없으면 앞으로 한국 교육은 미래가 없다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PISA 라고 전 국가의 교육을 순위로 데이터로 볼 수 있는 프로그램이 있다. 이 프로그램에서 한국은 상위권이나 자세히 생각해보면 &lt;strong&gt;주입식 교육의 결과임을 알 수 있다.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;생각을 스스로 하게하는 교육이 아닌 정답만을 고르는 교육의 결과를 볼 수 있다.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/N8rkO6gwf9g&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5UaJywOO6Mk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;다음 post 에서는 &lt;strong&gt;독일 교육의 역사&lt;/strong&gt;와 &lt;strong&gt;언제부터 파격적으로 정책이 변했는지&lt;/strong&gt; 볼 것이다.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 17:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//german-4/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//german-4/</guid>
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>Revolution</category>
        
        <category>system</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        
        <category>Germankr</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>특별한 교육정책을 선택한 독일정부! 그러면 독일사람들이 말하는 불만은?</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;특별한-교육정책을-선택한-독일정부-그러면-독일사람들은-불만이-없을까&quot;&gt;특별한 교육정책을 선택한 독일정부! 그러면 독일사람들은 불만이 없을까?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;[https://chingufreunde.com/ko/%EB%8F%85%EC%9D%BC-%EA%B5%90%EC%9C%A1-%EC%8B%9C%EC%8A%A4%ED%85%9C%EC%9D%98-%EB%8B%A8%EC%A0%90-feat-%EB%8F%85%EC%9D%BC%EC%9D%B8-c/](https://chingufreunde.com/ko/독일-교육-시스템의-단점-feat-독일인-c/)&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brunch.co.kr/@itsk2h/65&quot;&gt;독일 교육관련 Brunch link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;다른 사람의 눈으로 본 독일 교육의 단점도 볼 필요가 있다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;이 영상도 참고가 될거 같아서 같이 공유하고자 한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lIFKsF1oATE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.iamexpat.de/sites/default/files/styles/article--full/public/education-rural-germany-just-good-cities.jpg?itok=JJ3DNWZj&quot; alt=&quot;germany's education system&quot; title=&quot;germany's education system.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;우리는 독일의 교육이 단순히 좋다고 느낄 수 도 있다. “시험이 없다” “취업으로 이어지는 교육”등 을 떠올릴 수 있다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;하지만 교육정책은 단점도 있다는 것을 우리는 알고 있어야 한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;그러면 이제 독일 교육의 단점을 보자. 학생이 다양한 선택을 할 수 있지만 조금은 복잡하다.  또한 부모님의 직업과 재산에 따라서 독일 학생들은 교육수준, 교육 후 받는 임금수준이 달라질 수 있다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;독일은 유치원 (Kindergarten)을 보통 3 살부터 보내고, 3년후 6살에는 초등학교에 간다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;처음에 4년동안은 대부분 학생들이 그룬드슐레(Grundschule)를 다닌다. 의무교육 과정으로 똑같은 형태의 학교를 모든 학생들이 다닌다고 한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;그러면 이제 본격적인 교육은 10살부터 시작된다고 볼수있다&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;독일인이 문제점이라고 보는 부분은 초등학교(그룬드슐레(Grundschule) 졸업 후에 &lt;strong&gt;중등 고등 교육 단계로 갈 때 주 마다 다른 교육정책&lt;/strong&gt;을 학생이 선택 &lt;strong&gt;/ 그리고 집안의 영향에 따른 선택을 하는 학생&lt;/strong&gt;이 있다는 것이다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;그룬드슐레,(Grundschule)&lt;/strong&gt; 졸업 후에는 다음과 같은 과정이 있다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;하웁트슐레 (Hauptschule)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;가장 낮은 단계의 학교로 5년과정으로 교육을 받는다. 학생들은 졸업을 15살에 한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;레알슐레 (Realschule)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6년이 걸리고 학생들은 처음 2년을 다닌 후에 중심 과목을 선택한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;보통은 3 가지 유형이 있다. (1)기술/과학 (2)경제/회계 (3)예술 음악.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;그러면 이제 16살에 졸업하고 선택을 해야한다. 아우스빌둥이라고 불리는 (Ausbildung) 독일식 직업교육을 받거나 팍흐혹흐슐레 (Fachhochschule) 에서 더 공부를 하는 방향으로 선택할 수 있다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;김나지움 (Gymnasium)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;아비투어라고 불리는  (Abitur) 독일의 대학진학을 위한 시험을 치기 위한 교육받고 준비하는 교육기관에서 공부를 할 수 있다. 여기서는 제 2 외국어를 배우고 만약 레알슐레 (Realschule)를 다닌다면 김나지움으로 전학가능하다. 하지만 보통은 어렵고 그 이유는 레알슐레에서는 제 2 외국어를 배우지 않기 때문이다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;팍흐혹흐슐레 (Fachhochschule) (다른 주는 베루프콜리그(Berufskolleg)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2년동안 팍흐혹흐슐레에서 공부하고 졸업을 하면 레알슐레 졸업생에게는 아비투어 시험 응시 자격이 주어진다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;아비투어 시험이 끝난 후에 보통학생들은 팍흐혹흐슐레 (전문대, Fachhochschule)만 선택해야 한다. 실용적인 교육만을 받는 곳이고 처음에3주는 학교에서, 3주는 인턴쉽, 그 다음은 다시 3주동안 학교를 가는 커리큘럼으로 이루어진다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;김나지움과 팍흐혹흐슐레 졸업생은 2 가지 선택을 더 할 수 있고 첫번째로는 대학 진학,  두번째는 직업교육을 받는 미래를 선택한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gpseducation.oecd.org/Content/MapOfEducationSystem/DEU/DEU_2011_EN.png&quot; alt=&quot;germany's education system&quot; title=&quot;germany's education system.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;더 자세한 이해를 위해서 한글로 번역된 독일 학교제도 체계를 보여주고자 한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://w.namu.la/s/4c04439ddace647a2d023c8c30cc34433ee51033b551344305c20dd0cfc8da5d2dae814f8075f7623140d34fc639c5ff14d434f9573b26738f72da70b36956014b442f3926de9139f4e93b45355c31000ae49f39ce70d889ac3a7b60938e09e3&quot; alt=&quot;germany's education system&quot; title=&quot;germany's education system.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;여기서 &lt;strong&gt;독일인들이 말하는 문제점&lt;/strong&gt;이 나온다. 학생들의 부모가 재산이 많거나 부모의 직업이 좋다면 그 영향력이 학생에게 간다는 것이다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;예시로 부모가 변호사나 대기업 관리자라면 학생은 김나지움을 추천받는다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;성적에 따라서 레알슐레나 김나지움 진학여부를 알 수 있다. 만약 어떤 학생이 레알슐레를 가고싶다고 하면 성적이 필요 하다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;방송사 JTBC에 프로그램 차이나는 클래스에 나온 다니엘의 의견도 있다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;몃년전 시리아 난민의 이주를 독일이 받아들이고 수용한 적이 있다. 그로인해서 최근에는 학교에 교사수가 부족하다는 불만이 있다고도 한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;그리고 난민과 독일 학생들간의 문제도 조금씩 생긴다고 한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;정리하면 “부모의 배경과 부모의 직업이 어떤 경우에는 학생의 선택권을 넘어선다” 라고 나는 말 하고싶다.어떤 독일인은 가장 큰 문제점이 학생들에게 동기부여와 관심을 주기에는 부족하다고 말 한다.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;독일의 교육은 경쟁이 없고 교육비가 적다는 점, 사교육이 없고 다양한 선택지가 있다는 장점이 있다. 심지어 독일의 대학수학능력시험인 아비투어는 서술형이다. 부모들은 대부분 학교 시스템에 대해서 만족한다. 하지만 현지 사람들의 눈으로 보면 문제가 되는 부분도 조금은 있을 수 밖에 없다. 우리가 알 수 있는 한가지 사실은 아직도 독일의 교육 장점을 보고 독일로 가는 사람들이 있다는 것이다.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 15:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//german-3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//german-3/</guid>
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>Revolution</category>
        
        <category>system</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        
        <category>German</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why is Germany the perfect place to study abroad?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Germany is best country to study and learn new things, if you like to do study in your life. my opinion is Germany is a paradise of high education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently Germany is becoming a magnet for international students from all over the world. and a lot of international students want study in Germany. even include me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found some of the reasons why students prefer to study in this amazing country. you can see 11 reasons. And if you want more information, you can search for your self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.umultirank.org/export/sites/default/press-media/infographics/2019/Country-Facts/germany.png_1742451035.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;germany's education system.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &lt;strong&gt;Low or No Tuition Fees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;International student pay only around €250 per semester altogether, and Foreign students pay only a few administrative costs like student contribution, student union fee and a public transport ticket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A decision which came into power in October 2014, stated that all international students attending a public university in Germany would be free from paying normal tuition fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found an interesting some result. According to a survey conducted in 2018, 35.3% of prospective foreign students in Germany highlighted low or no tuition fee universities as the top reason why they would attend higher education in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) &lt;strong&gt;Top-Ranked Universities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on official recordings in 2018, Germany has 429 public higher education institution, and 106 are universities. German universities are above global higher education standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;even Some of the university is high ranking in the world.  that university supports to a student for universities for the quality of education, hands-on experiences during their studies, opportunities to improve academically during and after studies and most importantly the safe and friendly environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and some universities have a long great history. Germany universities have a worldwide reputation thanks to their recognized teaching and research excellence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so if you are studying in Germany, you can enjoy building upon a long and rich tradition of higher education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) &lt;strong&gt;Travel Europe on a student visa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a European student, you can stay in Germany to feel free. but If you are not a European citizen, and you want stay in Germany to study, you will have to apply for a Visa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you are enrolled on a summer school language program,  you will need to apply for a student visa that allows you to reside in Germany for more than 90 days, and also get a residency permit to become able to live and move around the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you can travel visa-free in the whole Schengen Area, which makes for a wonderful. this is a great opportunity for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you receive the letter of acceptance from the designated German University, it is recommendable to apply for a student visa at least 3 months prior to your intended departure (the time you are expected to be in Germany).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the residency permit, all your documentation will be sent to the Immigration Office of the German region where your University is stationed, and after every bureaucratic procedure is done you will be issued the residency permit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to obtain a student visa, however, there are certain criteria that need to be met. If you are travelling to Europe on such a permit, you will have to inform the designated authorities prior to your departure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) &lt;strong&gt;Countless Degree Courses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you can choose countless degree courses what you want to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an industrialized country, Germany has invested a lot in Engineering universities. Engineering programs are particularly valued at German universities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the list of traditional courses in German universities is expanding fast as a new study. fields are emerging accordingly with cutting-edge scientific improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you can learn new knowledge in a great field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if you want to study about the universe, in Germany it is likely you’ll find a program about it taught by the most regarded professionals in that particular field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) &lt;strong&gt;Globally Recognized Study Programs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The German university curriculum goal is subject to the constant provision and changing aiming to find, create comprehensive approaches to teaching and researching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of your course, you will be certified with a degree which is globally recognized and valued. and you will be getting new opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) &lt;strong&gt;Affordable Costs of Living&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the cost of living for international students in Germany is quite affordable. so if you do a bit of smart financial management or change your lifestyle, you can enjoy international students life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rent fee is one of the problems for study in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but you can choose a lot of options, and you can find some unit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cost of other goods and services like food, amenities, public transport and so on is not high&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) &lt;strong&gt;Work Opportunities For International Students&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The German law states that international students are allowed to work part-time for up to 20 hours a week or 120 full days of a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you can find jobs, for your life and you can make money for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) &lt;strong&gt;future Prospects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your degree issued from a German university is a highly respected and valued qualification all over the world. As an indication of this, German graduates enjoy a high employability in the global job market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) &lt;strong&gt;Learn a new Langauge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you can learn the German language while study, and you can get more opportunity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10) &lt;strong&gt;Diverse Community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;German nationals live in harmony with many foreigners who came here to work and live with their families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and German universities are attracting thousands of international students. so there is a lot of community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said in Germany you will encounter a diverse community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, you can make a lot of friends coming from all around the world and learn about their customs and traditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11) &lt;strong&gt;Cultural and Historical Heritage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Germany has a long, rich and complex history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you can to visit most of these cultural and historical gems, hear unbelievable stories related to them and collect unforgettable memories.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 23:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//german-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//german-2/</guid>
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>Revolution</category>
        
        <category>system</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        
        <category>German</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>the education system of Germany</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;why the education system of Germany is strong?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think one of the reasons is the German government policy is changed after WW2. I decided to do research on education for me and record on my Blog. Let’s see first what is the education system of Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.studying-in-germany.org/german-education-system/#qualifications-of-the-german-higher-education-system&quot;&gt;참고link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;this-is-how-the-german-school-system-works&quot;&gt;This is how the German school system works&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ministry closely collaborates with Federation and Landers (German states), educational institutions, organizations for supervising the entire activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Landers and the Federation (which has a minor role), they have a responsibility for education issues in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though, there are areas of cooperation in the education field for which such a distinction between both parts doesn’t exist. this is a school system structured in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;compulsory-education-in-germany&quot;&gt;Compulsory Education in Germany&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Is Considered as Compulsory Education in Germany?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All Germans have to accept primary and secondary education. it is a duty for all German education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ever since child reach the age of 6, up until they complete 9-year full-time schooling at Gymnasium, or 10 years of full-time years for other general education schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are youngsters fail to attend full-time classes at the general or vocational education schools, at upper secondary level, they’ve to attend part-time left-aside classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This applies even if they’ve already passed the period of their compulsory education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such an obligation is “Berufsschule Berufsschulpflicht” and lasts 3 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if your children who fail to attend at all such education and training, they’ve may be required to attend full-time classes and training (for vocational schools only).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this is important to Disabled youngsters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disabled youngsters have an obligation to complete compulsory education too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;they have to attend either a normal school or a special school.
“Sonderpadagogische Bildungseinrichtungen”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;one more thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;German compulsory education is included a participate in school lessons, as well as in other formal and informal schooling activities/events/projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, parents need to supervise study progress children for them and participate in school parent’s meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;here are the 5 levels German school system&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;here are the 5 levels German school system&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early Childhood Education. / 유아교육&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Primary Education. / 초등교육&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondary Education. / 중등교육&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tertiary Education. / 고등교육&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;continuing education. / 지속 교육&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and Here is germany’s education ststem&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.studying-in-germany.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/Germany-Education-System.png&quot; alt=&quot;germany's education system&quot; title=&quot;germany's education system .&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;early-childhood-education-in-germany&quot;&gt;Early Childhood Education in Germany&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;early Childhood Education is optional and cares that children between 0-6 of age receive in the Federal Territory of Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;who’s Responsible for the German Preschool Education?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supervision of the German pre-school education is mainly the responsibility of the State Youth Welfare Office “Landesjugendämter” of the respective Lander.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and they have responsibilities about issuing licenses for the preschool education and care institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;they have a preschool education operation license program. this program includes right child/staff ratio, properly qualifications educators, adequate space, appropriate equipment and hygiene, as well as the age-appropriate education program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the Institutions of Preschool Education in Germany&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;privately-run day-care centres are German pre-school education is largely offered. Preschool education providers are “Kinderkrippen” (crèches), child-minding centers, kindergarten, and day-care centres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;non-public organizations, such as Churches, Welfare or Parent’s Associations is get at Priority in offering childhood education services first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;privately-run day-care centres are German pre-school education is largely offered. Preschool education providers are “Kinderkrippen” (crèches), child-minding centers, kindergarten, and day-care centres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Priority in offering childhood education services is offered to non-public organizations, such as Churches, Welfare or Parent’s Associations. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.studying-in-germany.org/german-education-system/#compulsory-education-in-germany&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the German children how long time get Preschool Education?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Opening hours of the preschool education institutions are scheduled in cooperation between parents and managing staff. Usually, children stay a 7-hour day for education and care. and they get lunch and sometimes a midday break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;almost German children learn Methodology and Materials before Preschool Education in Germany.(Under the Age of 3 / over the Age of 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;privately-run day-care centres are German pre-school education is largely offered. Preschool education providers are “Kinderkrippen” (crèches), child-minding centres, kindergarten, and day-care centres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;non-public organizations, such as Churches, Welfare or Parent’s Associations is got at Priority in offering childhood education services first.
Priority in offering childhood education services is offered to non-public organizations, such as Churches, Welfare or Parent’s Associations. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.studying-in-germany.org/german-education-system/#compulsory-education-in-germany&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Children Under the Age of 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;they are learning communication skills amongst kids. Secondly, it is the development of their language skills through social interaction with other toddlers and adults. this is the core educational mission of German preschool education age under of 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Children over the age of 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;they are learning teamwork skills, along with their level of integration in daily life activities. this is the core educational mission of German preschool education age over of 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;they are learning teamwork skills, along with their level of integration in daily life activities. this is the core educational mission of German preschool education age over of 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;here are 7 things important Keypoint areas of German preschool education of children older than 2 are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) language, writing, communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(2) personal and social development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(3) development of values and religious education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(4) mathematics, natural sciences, (information) technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(5) fine arts/working with different media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(6) body, movement, health and.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(7) nature and cultural environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;do they have any Assessment of the Educational Achievements for Preschool Education?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;no They doesn’t have. instead, educators or trainers can help children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;children constantly supervised by their educators or trainers regarding their attainment from learning activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, educators are do discussed with parents of the children. and parents agree on the further development of kids’ learning skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**What If My Child Isn’t yet Ready to Begin Compulsory School Studies? **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Schulkindergärten”, or a Preliminary Class “Vorklassen” is the second option for the child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;german-primary-education&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;German Primary Education&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Is Considered Preschool Education in Germany?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;all German Primary school student is obliged to attend mandatory education through mixed-ability classes for children of age 6 until they complete grade 4 (or 6 in Berlin and Brandenburg) of school studies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grundschule (primary school) offer mandatory education through mixed-ability classes for children of age 6 until they complete grade 4 (or 6 in Berlin and Brandenburg) of school studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two primary school education systems in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) In a 5-day school week pre-education system, there’re 188 teaching days/annually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) In a 6-day school week preschool system, there’re 208 days of teaching/annually, by including also teachings during 2 Saturdays/every month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Primary school student is obliged to attend 20 to 29 courses / and 20-22 in 1 week, in the first year. and Primary school courses normally last up to 45 minutes. During, 1 day up to 6 courses can be taught.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and we need to know this. this is The core objective of the German primary education. the development of essential understanding, skills, abilities and key competencies amongst pupils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;even they don’t have a final graduation test but Grading System in German Primary Schools.By completing lessons of grade 1, children are automatically transferred to the grade 2, regardless level of knowledge attained during such studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting from grade 2, these children are awarded a suitable mark, independence to the level of knowledge they’ve attained during studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;instead, If failing to pass the grade, children have to repeat the grade lessons once more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;here is The progress of pupils in German primary schools evaluated upon a 6-mark grading system as follows&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 (very good).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 (good).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 (satisfactory).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 (adequate).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5 (poor).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6 (very poor).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;german-second-education&quot;&gt;German second Education&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondary Education is separated into lower secondary level “Sekundarstufe I” and upper secondary level “Sekundarstufe II”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this is lower secondary education.  education offered for pupils of age 10 – 15/16 in grades 5/7 to 9/10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this Lessons purpose for getting ready the upper level of secondary education. and it’s upper secondary education. education that pupils of age 15/16 – 18/who have completed a lower level of the secondary school receive for the purpose of getting a university entrance qualification or a vocational qualification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This level purpose all the courses of lower secondary level which built the basis of knowledge of the participating pupils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Types of Secondary Schools in Germany&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Federal country of Germany offers secondary education in public and private schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Germany’s publicly-funded secondary schools are:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; ♦︎ &lt;strong&gt;German high schools issuing specialized qualifications in one study area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Gymnasium”.&lt;/strong&gt; Providing intensive and in-depth general education, general knowledge for      university studies, and for scientific work. It normally covers schooling years from grade 5-12 or 5-13,     leading to an “Allgemeine Hochschulreife” known as “Abitur”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Hauptschule”.&lt;/strong&gt; Teaching basic general education, leading to a vocational or university entrance qualification. Education in such school lasts from grade 5-9, and sometimes includes the grade 10 as well, leading to a “Hauptschulabschluss”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Realschule”.&lt;/strong&gt; Offering more extensive education, leading to a vocational or university entrance qualification. It usually covers schooling years from grade 5 to 10, “Realschulabschluss”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;German schools with more than one study course “Schularten mit mehreren Bildungsgängen”.&lt;/strong&gt; They offer 2-3 different study subjects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;♦︎ &lt;strong&gt;German vocational schools.&lt;/strong&gt; They offer lessons and practical placement, known as a dual system. These are the types of vocational schools available in Germany:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Fachoberschule”.&lt;/strong&gt; Providing 2-year education to the holders of maturity certificate “Mittlerer Schulabschluss” leading to a “Fachhochschulreife”, entitling holder to enter a university of applied sciences. If a 13 grade is held in this institution, a pupil completing it can receive a “Fachgebundene Hochschulreife” or an “Abitur”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Berufsoberschule”.&lt;/strong&gt; Providing a 2-year general and in-depth education and training regarding initial vocational knowledge and training obtained during previous education, leading to a vocational qualification (or Abitur – by proving the good command in second foreign language). There is also a 3/4 year course of study which is aimed at getting a double qualification, both vocational and higher education qualification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Berufsfachschule”.&lt;/strong&gt; Offering education for one or few professions which require formal recognition or leading to a vocational training qualification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Berufsschule”.&lt;/strong&gt; Delivering practically-oriented and interdisciplinary lessons and skills, which prepare pupils for further vocational education or for a job in a profession. They do that based on the dual system, education and training combined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Berufliches Gymnasium”.&lt;/strong&gt; Providing a 3-year long secondary education program, leading to an Abitur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Germany’s private secondary schools are the following:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·    &lt;strong&gt;Alternative schools “Ersatzschulen”.&lt;/strong&gt; Providing equal lessons and courses as public secondary schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complementary schools “Ergänzungsschulen”.&lt;/strong&gt; Teaching additional courses, despite those that are also offered in the public secondary schools. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.studying-in-germany.org/german-education-system/#compulsory-education-in-germany&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here Are 4 things German secondary education objectives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) Engaging children intellectually, emotionally and physically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(2) Teaching them independence, decision making, as well as personal, social and political responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(3 )Assisting them in attaining their educational goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(4 )Supporting them in advancing their specialist knowledge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The progress of pupils in the German secondary schools is evaluated upon a 6-mark grading system as follows&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 (very good).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 (good).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 (satisfactory).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 (adequate).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5 (poor).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6 (very poor).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/welcome-center-germany.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/German-Education-System-696x464.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;germany's education system&quot; title=&quot;germany's education system .&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;german-tertiary-education&quot;&gt;German Tertiary Education&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;German tertiary education in Germany provides higher education for qualifying individuals, who before all, have completed secondary education in Germany or abroad which entitles them to enter higher education studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** &lt;strong&gt;Who’s Responsible for Supervision of German Tertiary Education?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;German Tertiary Education is following Higher education Basic law. independently about managing the scholarship awarding, research and teaching activity in institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so German Tertiary Education is helpful to a student. even they can study more if they want to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s see Institutions of German Tertiary Education. As you can found they have a lot of Institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·    Universities “&lt;em&gt;Universit&lt;strong&gt;ä&lt;/strong&gt;ten”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;and Equal Institutions**.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·    “Technische Hochschulen”/”Technische Universitäten”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·    “Pädagogische Hochschulen”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·    Theological colleges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·    Universities of Applied Sciences &lt;em&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;Fachhochschulen&lt;/strong&gt;”.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·    Art and Music Colleges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·    Higher Education Institutions for Federal Armed Forces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·    Higher Education Institutions Offering Dual Studies &lt;em&gt;“**Berufsakademie”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;(BA).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;·    Institutions of Continuing Vocational Education &lt;em&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;Fachschulen&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/em&gt; And &lt;em&gt;“**Fachakademien”&lt;/em&gt; In Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;ccording to the International Standard Classification of Education (ISCED), the education received from these institutions is equal to the first level of higher education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;even they can study more if they want to do that. German universities have a lot of study courses. this is Qualifications of the German Higher Education System. You can found 3 differently way higher Education System.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bachelor&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Degree – First German Higher Education Qualification&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first higher education qualification in Germany is the Bachelor degree. The standard period of study “&lt;em&gt;Regelstudienzeit&lt;/em&gt;” in a Bachelor program is 6 semesters, or 3 full academic years.  In Universities of Applied Sciences bachelor studies last 6-7 semesters, by also including the practical work. In German Colleges of Art and Music such studies last about 8 semesters or 4 academic years. In Professional Academies they last 3 academic years. In Fachschulen bachelor degree studies last 2 academic years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magister Degree – Second German Higher Education Qualification.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second higher education qualification in Germany is the Master degree. It takes 2 -4 semesters to complete studies in a German master degree program. In universities and equal institutions as well as college of art and music, this period is mostly 4 semesters. In Fachhochschulen this period is 3-4 semesters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To complete a Master degree, students must achieve 300 ECTS credit points also including the points received by the earlier qualification. To complete a Master degree, a student whose earlier qualification is a Bachelor degree, must achieve 360 ECTS points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;) &lt;strong&gt;PhD&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Degree –&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;third&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;German Higher Education Qualification.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third higher education qualification in Germany is the PHD degree. This is a program that is embraced by the most qualified students, and can be taken at German universities and equivalent institutions, in collaboration with non-university research institutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no standardized period for completing doctoral studies, as this is a more in-depth and individual specialization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the German Higher Education System has an exam for entrance university or college for study. but almost a student doesn’t pay the school fee. because of German government support to students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we can figure out together, the secret of the German education, and more history about education. we will talk on next post about, why the education system of Germany is strong, and weakness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 17:20:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//german/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//german/</guid>
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>Revolution</category>
        
        <category>system</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        
        <category>German</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
